SANJAYA RATHNAYAKA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A positive team player with over 14 years of technical expertise, who is also comfortable working independently. Experience in developing trusting relationships with customers. Quick learner, adapting easily to changing environments. Technical experience with a variety of telecommunications and data hardware and software applications in the field as well as remotely. Currently, seeking to further professional and career development with a new challenging position

WORK HISTORY

Technical Manager, 01/2018 - 09/2021 Dayaratne Holdings Pvt Ltd, Sri Lanka

- Installation, testing and configuration of company ERP Systems and Asset Management Systems, including network cabling and Wi-Fi
- Handling IT support queries when office based including logging and reporting hardware faults with 3rd party suppliers.
- Configure, maintain, Windows servers and support WAN technologies to include VPN, routers, and firewalls
- Carry out software and hardware upgrades on site or remotely
- Assist in establishing and maintaining all network technologies, including switches and access points
- Provide backups and disaster recovery for agreed IT solutions
- Meeting with the user community and gathering requirements, conducting regular team meetings, and tracking progress and reporting directly to the CEO

Technical Support Analyst, 07/2017 - 01/2018 Debenhams Hong Kong Ltd, Sri Lanka

- Provide primary technical support to office users on various technical issues and problems relating to hardware, software, and peripherals
- Diagnose, analyse, and resolve complicated problem scenarios, and conduct root cause analysis, create checklists for common issues, and establish processes and controls to prevent problems.
- Providing users with training and information regarding the use of new systems

- West Bridgford,
 Nottingham,
 United Kingdom
- 07888 145262
- sanjayaarc@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/sanjaya-rathnayaka-8631a735

KEY SKILLS

- GEPON, LAN, WAN and VPN
- Strong knowledge of Windows operating Systems (7,8,10) and Server Technologies (2008,2016) and Mac OS
- Solid understanding of DHCP, DNS, Active Directory and Virtualisation
- Experience in managing wireless networks, network terminations, PABX, VOIP and cisco products
- Experience with C#.NET, JAVA
- Experience with computer maintenance and troubleshooting
- Experience with CCTV, access control systems, GPS, and GSM tracking systems

EDUCATION

PG Dip – Cyber Security 2022 - 2024 University of Essex – UK

MCSA 70-740 (Windows Server 2016), CCNA 200-120 (Routing & Switching), 2018/2019
WinSYS Networks - Sri Lanka

Certificate in FTTH Installation (Double/ Triple Play), 2011 ETISALAT Academy - U.A.E

National Diploma in IT (NVQ 5) 2006

IT Executive, 11/2013 - 07/2017

Frostaire Industries (Pvt) Ltd, Sri Lanka

- Direct SAGE 50 (accounting, payroll and HRM modules) as an administrator
- Conduct user training on SAGE 50 and SAGE CRM
- Direct administration of company LAN & WAN, computer systems and telephone systems
- Administrator of CCTV, fingerprint, fuel cards and guard patrol systems
- Manage all vehicles and field staff using GPS and GSM tracking systems
- Oversee new system facilitation, current system enhancements
- Manage internal/external application upgrades.

Telecommunication Specialist, 09/2010 - 10/2013 ETISALAT, Dubai U.A.E

- Installation and troubleshooting of eLife 3P services, IPTV, ADSL, DEL residential services
- Migrate copper base networks to GEPON through an understanding of FTTH network
- Installation and configuration of ADSL routers, ethernet switches, cisco managed routers, IPTV, telephone services and PABX devices
- Installing and troubleshooting data devices ISDN BRI, SIP-Trunks and IAD Devices
- Hand experience in fiber termination with specialist tools (Fujikura, Sumitomo, and corning tool kits)
- Proactively manage customer relationships
- Continuously educate customers on products/features an end to end solutions
- Responsible for aligning activities to promote company products and drive new solutions.

Computer Programmer, 07/2008 - 09/2010

Fentons Ltd, Sri Lanka

- Write, analyse, review, and test computer programs and apply knowledge of computing capabilities, subject matter, and symbolic logic
- Correct errors by making appropriate changes and then rechecking the program to ensure that desired results are produced

Vocational Training Auth - Sri Lanka

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- DAYARATNE HOLDINGS As the technical manager, conducted company MIS user training and employee inductions
- ETISALAT U.A.E A proven record of accomplishment in resolving complex customer issues and equipment field repair

LICENSE

Full UK Driving License Holder

EFERENCES

Reference available upon request